Using the DMAIC Method in a PFSS Environment
Welcome back to this session on PFSS, Processing for Six Sigma.
Recall, that we had left off with looking at our
optimal setting here for the vital few of our operation.
That if we find the optimal setting
of a vital few, of a critical to process variable, yield goes up. And as the yield goes up here,
and the yield goes up here, and the yield goes up there,
by finding the CTP's here, here, and here.
And finding their optimal settings, the throughput yield goes up.
The rolled throughput yield. As it goes up, profit goes up. That simple.
Now, we’ve got an interesting case here. Here's the case.
There are natural variations. There are variables that controls that X.
For example, if this is a temperature setting. Well, if you set the temperature at 104°F.
There's going to be variation there, because the switch may fall
to as low as 102° before it kicks on to raise the temperature back up.
And it may raise to 106 before it kicks off. To where 104 is the average.
So, what we see is variation. We see variation.
And what we want to do is to look out here at the tails.
See, that's above the upper spec and the lower spec. We want to minimize that.
So, we want to take this process capability, for that knob, from a condition like that
to a condition like this. Can you see that real good?
I want to narrow the bandwidth of operation of this process.
So, that I maximize the yield of this.
I don't have all this over hang out here. As the yield of this CTP goes up,
the rolled throughput yield goes up. If I do that for every critical to process characteristic.
Narrow it's operating bandwidth. Now that's what we mean by process capability
So, the purpose of Processing for Six Sigma is to go in and do a simple thing.
D M A I C.
I want to define the CTQ’s. I want to measure the CTQ’s.
I want to analyze the CTQ’s . I want to improve the CTP’s.
See, I want to also identify my CTP’s here, that's the crossover.
And then control those CTP's, over time. I want to control this bandwidth.
Keeping it narrow and from wiggling around over time.
For temperature, which is a vital few variable here, a critical to process variable.
I want to do it for each of those critical to process variables.
As that occurs, this yield or the capability of this step increases.
If I do that here, here and here.
Then collectively, the whole process improves.
As that process improves, say that's an HR process with hiring people.
As it improves and my legal processes improve,
and my engineering processes improve. Guess what happens to the company?
It gets better. And that's the purpose of Processing for Six Sigma.
Identify all these variables and improve their performance capability.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.